Three, two, one.
3 2 1
What do you want to do next?
接下来你想玩什么?
Uh, swings?
秋千?
Okay. Um, crawl tube?
好吧 那钻钻乐?
Nah. Nah?
- 不要 - 不要吗?
Well, I think we're running out of options, honey.
那恐怕没什么可以玩的了呢 宝贝
I want to go on the merry-go-round. The m- again?
- 我要去玩旋转木马 - 旋...还要玩?
But this time all by myself.
但这次要我一个人坐
I don't know, jellybean. Daddy, I'm six.
- 这我可说不好 宝贝 - 爸比 我都六岁了
I'm not a baby anymore.
不是小孩子了
Please?
拜托嘛
Thank you.
谢谢
You ready? Uh-huh.
准备好了吗
All right. Come here.
好了 来吧
I'll take beary.
把小熊给我
Mm. Now you promise you're not gonna tell mommy, right?
现在你要答应我不会告诉妈妈 好吗?
She'll kick my butt if she finds out.
要是被她知道 我会被打屁股的
Pinky swear.
打勾勾
All right. Go get 'em.
好了 去吧
Remember to hold on tight. I will.
- 一定要抓牢哟 - 我会的
Stop the ride!
快停下
Emily!
Emily!
Emily, where are you?
Emily 你在哪儿
Em?
Em?
Emily?
Emily?
Emily, where are you, honey?
Emily 宝贝儿你在哪里
Oh, Em.
Em
Emily.
Emily
Honey?
亲爱的
Help me!
来人啊
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第19集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第19集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 时间轴：绿
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：王母娘娘 FF永爱HW 校对：酒囊饭袋 时间轴：绿
Is that our precious little bundle of tumor?
那是咱的宝贝小肿瘤吗
They grow up so fast, don't they?
长得可真快啊 是吧
How did you know I was here? How do you think?
- 你怎么知道我在这儿 - 你说呢
Foreman.
Foreman
Actually, that would have been easier. No, I followed you.
你别说 问他还真就容易多了 不是 我跟踪你来着
It didn't occur to you that that might mean I don't want you involved in my cancer treatment?
你就没想过 我或许是不想你 参与到我治疗癌症的过程中呢
I'm not here as a doctor. I'm here as a towering pillar of strength.
我不是作为医生的身份来的 我是来作你强有力的支柱的
Be a pillar in the parking lot. No.
- 去停车场当柱子吧 - 不要
How many times have I told you I wanted to be alone and you've made yourself a pain in the ass?
有多少次我想一个人待着 可你还是一个劲儿地缠着我不放?
I owe you.
这是我欠你的
My word, not a word.
我的话 都不算数
Realizing I'm most likely going to regret this,
虽然明知道我以后肯定会后悔
all right.
不过好吧
What-what are you doing?
你在干什么
My best friend has cancer.
我的死党得了癌症
Cut me some slack.
容我破罐子破摔一下嘛
Also, spring break.
顺便过个春假
I'm on vacation.
我正在休假中
Although looking at you now, I can tell the wet T-shirt contest
尽管此时看着你 我看得出湿身T恤比赛
is probably gonna suck.
应该会很无趣
House taking time off is a bad sign.
House休息这可是坏兆头啊
"A bad sign. "
"坏兆头"
You think the apocalypse is coming because House wants to be there for Wilson?
你是说因为House想要支持Wilson 世界末日就要来了吗?
Yes. You're new.
是的 你是新来的不了解情况
We got a case.
有案子了
Six-year-old with a nosebleed and breathing problems.
6岁儿童流鼻血 呼吸障碍
She was born with a rare mutation of A-T.
她天生就有罕见的A-T突变 (共济失调毛细血管扩张综合征)
Emily has a unique variant on both of her ATM genes.
Emily的两种ATM基因都有独特变异 (ATM基因 抑癌基因)
Her disorder mimics A-T, but not all of the symptoms.
她的伪A-T基因紊乱 但没有出现全部症状
This is Dr. Elizabeth Lawson.
这位是Elizabeth Lawson医生
She's a developmental geneticist attached to JHU and an expert on the girl's condition.
她是约翰霍普金斯大学的发育遗传学家 也是这小女孩病症的专家
Elizabeth Lawson.
Elizabeth Lawson
Emily Lawson.
Emily Lawson
I'm here as a doctor, not a mother.
我是以医生身份来的 不是一位母亲
Nosebleeds and breathing problems are common symptoms of ataxia telangiectasia.
流鼻血和呼吸障碍 都是AT综合征的常见症状
We could just be seeing the natural progression- - It's not.
- 我们可以只考虑正常的发病 - 不是的
A- T patients have a life expectancy of 20 years.
A- T病人的寿命只有20年
Emily is only six. It's something else.
Emily只有六岁 是别的问题
I examined her lungs two days ago. They're functioning normally.
两天前我检查过她的肺部 功能正常
It says she fell off a carousel. Head trauma-
上面说她是从旋转木马上摔下来的 头部受创...
If the diagnosis was easy, I wouldn't need you people.
要是这么容易诊断 我就不用麻烦几位了
I'm here because, according to Eric, you're the best.
我来是因为  Eric说 你们是最出色的
We are.
我们确实是
Have you considered Wegener's granulomatosis?
你有想过韦格纳肉芽肿吗? (一种坏死性肉芽肿性血管炎)
It's a good fit.
很吻合呢
But she can't have X-rays. A- T makes her hypersensitive to ionizing radiation.
可是她不能拍X光 A-T让她对离子放射非常敏感
I'll get her prepped for an MRI.
我会帮她准备做MRI的
She knows more about her daughter's genetic condition than any of you.
她比你们任何人都清楚女儿的基因状况
She'll be an asset.
会有需要她的时候
Or she won't,
或者不会
Eric.
Eric
This isn't a request. Use her.
这不是请求 让她帮忙
The tumor's spread to the surrounding tissue.
肿瘤扩散到了周围的组织
We're gonna have to shrink it before we remove it surgically.
我们要在手术摘除前将其缩小
I'm more interested in exactly how you plan to do that, Mike.
我更感兴趣的是 你打算怎么做 Mike
We start conservative. Daily radiation treatments for three weeks.
我们先采取保守治疗 连续三周每天进行放射治疗
And, if it doesn't shrink enough after that, we'll add the chemo-
如果这样不能让肿瘤缩小到理想程度 就要加入化疗
And, if it hasn't shrunk enough after that, I'm dead.
如果这样还不理想的话 我就上西天了
Look, you have over a 75% chance that the radiation alone is enough.
听我说 你有超过75%的可能性 只需要放射治疗就够了
Relax. Caught this in time.
别担心 发现得很及时
Catching it in time would have been before it invaded the tissue around my thymus.
在它扩散到我胸腺周围其他组织前发现 才是及时
I want the radiation and the chemo concurrently.
我要放射和化疗同时进行
Why stress your immune system unnecessarily?
干嘛要给你的免疫系统增加不必要的压力呢
Let's just go with my plan, okay?
就按照我的计划进行 好吗
The radiation first - I'm gonna get a second opinion.
- 先放射治疗 - 我要另请高明了
Are you serious?
你说真的吗
Look, I've seen you recommend this exact treatment
我可是见过你很多次
dozens of times. We're done here.
- 都向病人建议这个治疗方案的 - 就这样吧
I'll look for a doctor with some actual balls.
我要找个有种的医生
Hey, you need to talk to your friend. He's embarrassing himself.
嘿 你得跟你朋友谈谈 他这是自取其辱
A doctor should be able to handle his own illness with a little bit more dignity.
做医生的 就应该能更有尊严地面对自己的病情
I agree with Wilson. My recommended treatment is sound.
- 我同意Wilson的意见 - 我的推荐方案是很稳妥的
No, I meant about the ball-less part. Explains the office.
不 我是指你没种的部分 难怪这办公室这德行了
It was a merry-go-round.
不过是旋转木马
She's a kid, Liz. We were having fun. You should try it sometime.
她是个小孩子 Liz 我们玩的很开心 你应该试试看呢
Fun? She's six, not you.
开心? 她是六岁 可你不是啊
You know she has balance issues.
你知道她有失衡的问题
I know that she's-
我知道她...
This is Emily's father, Simon.
这位是Emily的父亲 Simon
He was with her when the symptoms occurred.
发病时他就在她身边
I had her all week. She was fine. We could come back.
- 整个星期都是我带着她 什么事都没有 - 我们可以一会儿再来
No need. Patient's ready for transport.
没必要 病人准备好转移了
Wake up, sleepy head.
醒醒吧 小瞌睡虫
I saw it in the gift shop.
我是在礼品店里看到的
I know how much you like them. Thanks.
- 我知道你肯定喜欢 - 谢谢
They're gonna take you for an MRI now.
他们现在要带你去做MRI
It means "magic really cool images. "
意思是"神奇无比的图像"
I thought it stood for "magnetic resonance imaging. "
我以为是"核磁共振"的意思呢
We've spent a lot of time in hospitals.
我们是医院的常客
B-9.
B-9
- Hit. And I hate you.
中了 我恨你
Ugh. I'm done. I sunk your battleship?
- 不玩了 - 我击中了你的战舰?
No. But I think I'm gonna puke.
没 不过我想我要吐了
Good. Now that you're sufficiently buzzed,
很好 现在你充分喝醉了
what was the reason behind you freaking out on Kondo?
你到底为什么在Kondo面前抓狂
Are you scared? Are you in denial?
你是害怕吗? 你在逃避吗
I know you get confused any time someone thinks that you're wrong,
我知道你经常会搞不明白 怎么会有人觉得你是错的
but it's not considered freaking out for a patient to ask for a second opinion.
但是病人想要有第二种治疗建议 并不等于就是抓狂
Okay, well, here it is.
好吧 是这样的
Kondo is right. You should be in radiology right now.
Kondo是对的 你应该马上接受发射治疗
Well done. You've kept your word for almost two hours.
厉害啊 你居然憋了快两个小时才说出来
Every day you wait, our pal toomie is growing larger in your chest.
你多等一天 咱的肿瘤小弟 就会在你胸腔里长大一些
If you want to live, stop screwing around and do something about it.
你要是想活命 就别再犯浑 积极对待
Good idea.
好主意
I think I'll start with spending spring break
我想我就先从一个人过春假
on my own.
开始吧
How you feeling in there, Emily? Good, I guess.
- 你还好吗 Emily? - 挺好的吧
Is something wrong?
有什么不舒服吗
I was only pretending to be asleep.
我是假装睡着了
You think that's dishonest?
你觉得这样是不是不诚实?
Uh, that's-
这个...
My daughters do that too.
我女儿也会这样的
But they know that sometimes, when it seems like mommy and daddy are fighting, it's really
但是他们知道 有时爸爸妈妈看起来像是在吵架
only because they're worried about you.
但其实都是因为很担心你
And does your wife ever want a divorce?
那你妻子有想过要离婚吗
No. Everything's fine at home.
没有 一切都很好
Hold still now. No more talking.
依然是一家人 不要再说话了
What do you think of her mother?
你对她妈妈有什么看法
She called her daughter "the patient".
她称自己女儿是"病人"
If my kids were born with an expiration date,
如果我女儿出生就被判了死刑
- I don't- - Ow!
我不会...
Where does it hurt? I want my daddy. Where's my daddy?
- 哪里疼? - 我要爸爸 爸爸在哪里
We were able to restore circulation to her hands
我们在发生永久性伤害之前 恢复了她手部和脚部的血液循环
and feet before any permanent damage set in. Primary Raynaud's?
原发性雷诺病? (雷诺病:肢端动脉痉挛症)
The cold inside the MRI room could have set it off.
有可能是MRI室的冷气刺激病发的
Stress can also precipitate the condition.
压力也会促使病情早发
She's shown no evidence of cold sensitivity, and she has no problems with MRI machines.
她没有过任何怕冷问题 对MRI机器也没有恐惧
There are other kinds of stress. She heard you and your husband fighting.
还有其他方面的压力 她听到你和丈夫吵架了
Unfortunately, she's heard a lot worse than that before.
很遗憾 她以前听到过我们吵得更凶
It's not stress.
不是压力问题
Could be secondary Raynaud's.
可能是继发性雷诺病
Lupus is consistent with Emily's symptoms.
红斑狼疮也和Emily的症状相吻合
Her lymph nodes aren't enlarged, and she has shown no signs
她的淋巴结并没有肿大
It could be heavy metal poisoning. From what? The carousel?
- 有可能是严重的金属中毒 - 因为什么造成的? 旋转木马吗?
She was only on it for a minute.
她只在上面坐了一分钟而已
Simon moved into an old apartment building three weeks ago.
Simon三周前搬到一栋老房子里住
I'm sure he has no idea what the insulation's made of,
我相信他不知道隔热材料是用什么做的
what kind of paint.
以及用的哪种油漆
He's a good father, but when it comes to Emily's health-
他是个好父亲 但是在关系到Emily健康的问题时...
I'm gonna get his keys and check for environmentals.
我去拿他的钥匙 检查一下环境
Lupus is a better fit.
红斑狼疮更吻合
I don't mean to pull rank here, but I am her mother.
我并不是想仗势欺人 但我是她的妈妈
I thought you said you were here as a doctor.
你不是说以医生身份来的吗
And as a doctor, I need parental consent. See above.
作为一名医生 我需要父母的许可 详见上述材料
While I'm gone,
我不在的时候
please start her on Chelation Therapy.
请开始给她进行蛰合治疗
She's the mother.
她是妈妈
So let's treat her like any other mother.
所以咱们就把她当作是个普通妈妈吧
I think we just hit the environmental mother lode.
看来咱们发现了母亲的环境源泉
Funny she never mentioned an entire basement
搞笑的是 她居然没提起过一整间地下室
full of dangerous chemicals and drugs.
都是危险的化学物品和药物
You think she'd even let Emily down here?
你觉得她会让Emily到这儿来吗
Yeah.
是的
Apparently a lot.
显然经常来
You ever heard of Lex-2? Read about it.
- 你听说过Lex-2吗? - 看到过
It's an experimental aminoglycoside antibiotic.
是一种实验性氨基糖苷类抗生素
Supposedly it can override DNA errors in the ATM gene.
据说可以改变ATM基因中的DNA错误
Doesn't mean she's giving it to her daughter.
不代表她有用在自己女儿身上
Anyone studying A-T would be researching it.
任何研究A-T的人都会研究它的
How?
怎么做
You see any lab rats down here?
你看到这里有小白老鼠吗
The only cage I see is right there.
我看到的唯一一个笼子就是这里
Go away.
走开
I have a headache.
我头疼
We don't have to have sex.
咱们不一定非要上床的
Sometimes it's nice just to cuddle and talk.
有时只是抱抱 聊聊天就很好了
Me first. You don't want a second opinion.
我先说 你不想要听什么第二种意见
You're already on your fifth.
你自己问过五个人了
You got Evans at Mercy, Shaw at County, Foster at Johns Hopkins.
你有仁爱的Evans 郡医院的Shaw 约翰霍普金斯的Foster
And every one of them has given you the same advice.
他们每个人都给了你同样的答案
You're nuts.
你真是疯了
You don't just want chemo.
你不仅想要做化疗
You want a dose so high,
还一次就要那么高的剂量
there's a one-in-three chance it'll kill you outright.
让你有1/3的几率立马见上帝
Question is,
问题是
why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我呢
Because you knew I'd stop you.
因为你知道我一定会阻止你
Which means you've already found someone
也就是说 你已经找到了一个
insane enough or desperate enough
够神经 或者够绝望的人
to give you what amounts to a death dose of chemicals.
可以给你一次致死的剂量
But who would be that stupid?
可是谁会这么蠢呢
I'm thinking that the who is you.
我想这个人就是你自己
Where exactly were you planning on killing yourself?
你打算让自己葬身于何处呢
'Cause I don't think Foreman is gonna let you do it here.
因为我想Foreman是不会让你在这儿动手的
My place.
我家
I've been stockpiling equipment. No.
我一直在进行储备 不
No! Stop.
不 住手
I'm still healthy.
我还是健康的
Why not go the extreme route now when there's a better chance of surviving it?
如果走极端让我更有可能活下来 为什么不试试看?
Statistically, this treatment has about the same chance
统计来说 这种治疗和胸腺瘤
of killing you as the thymoma does.
同样能够要你的命
But a hell of a lot faster.
但是要快得多
Nancy Wells, cervical cancer, 70% survival rate.
Nancy Wells 子宫颈癌 70%的存活率
Died November 6, 1998,
1998年11月6日死亡
64 years old.
64岁
Bernie Jones, melanoma, 89% survival rate.
Bernie Jones 黑肿瘤 89% 的存活率
October 10, 1999. He was 52.
1999年10月10日死亡 52岁
John Taylor. Thyroid.
John Taylor 甲状腺癌
96% survival rate.
96% 的存活率
I promised him he'd be fine.
我跟他保证会没事的
Eight years old.
8岁
I am not going to die slowly in a hospital bed under fluorescent lighting
我不要躺在医院的病床上 在荧光灯下慢慢死去
with people stopping by to gawk and lie about how I look.
看着人们前来探望 对我目瞪口呆 撒谎说我看起来很好
Even a small chance of that happening is too big a chance for me.
就算再小的可能性 对我来说都是很大的可能
You're an idiot.
你这个白痴
And the odds say you're gonna die.
估计你是死定了
We'll do it at my place.
咱们还是去我家吧
The only environmental factors we think
我们认为唯一引起你女儿发病的环境因素
caused your daughter's illness are the ones you shot her full of.
是你给她注射的那些药物
I tested the drug. This is what I did for a living for ten years.
我试验过那些药的 10年来我都是靠这个赚钱讨生活的
She's your child, not a Guinea pig. I tested it first.
- 她是你女儿 不是天竺鼠 - 我先试过的
On myself.
在我自己身上
And in six months, I didn't document any adverse effects.
六个月的时间里 我没有出现任何不良反应
A trial of one is basically irrelevant.
只在一个人身上做实验根本不可靠
Respiratory infections are common with A-T.
呼吸器官感染是A-T的常见病症
With Emily's mutation, they are deadly, and they get worse every year.
以Emily的变异情况 这些都是致命的 每年都会恶化
Lex-2 won't be approved for at least the next five years.
Lex-2在未来五年内都不会获得批准
Emily, on the other hand,
Emily 相反
wouldn't have survived the winter.
可能连这个冬天都活不过
What was I supposed to do?
你让我怎么办
There's a reason for FDA requirements.
FDA的药物批准要求是有原因的
A study at Jackson Memorial- I know about Gaines' research.
- 杰克逊纪念医院的一项研究 - 我知道Gaines的研究
He's publishing next month. Was. I just spoke to him.
- 下个月就会发表 - 本来是的 我刚和他谈过
His team just linked the use of Lex-2 to renal failure in mice and rats.
他的团队刚刚发现Lex-2 导致老鼠出现了肾脏衰竭
She needs an ultrasound guided renal biopsy
她需要超声波引导下的 经皮肾穿刺活检术进行检查
To stupidity.
为白痴干杯
Mm, not quite done.
还不能喝
To muscle aches, spasms.
为肌肉痛  痉挛
To your joints feeling like they're being ripped out and replaced with shards of broken glass.
为你的关节感觉像是被扯断 用碎玻璃片取代而干杯
Should I be writing any of this down?
要我写下来么
Your stomach fills with bile.
胃里翻江倒海
When you vomit, it feels like someone's forcing a white hot hammer down your esophagus,
呕吐的时候 就像是有人用一把热铁锤 蹂躏你的食道
tearing your flesh.
将你四分五裂
Blood's dripping down the back of your throat, choking and gagging you
血从你的喉咙低落 让你哽噎
with the slick, coppery taste of burnt pennies.
用铁锈般苦涩的味道堵得你喘不上气
I am an Oncologist. I know-
我是肿瘤学专家 我知道
If you did, we wouldn't be sitting here.
你要是知道 咱们就不会坐在这儿了
Day two: Your white blood cells are gone,
第二天 你的白血球不见了
opening up your system to attack.
让你的系统随时等待袭击
Your temperature skyrockets. One second, your skin feels like it's on fire.
体温跌宕起伏 前一秒 你的皮肤还感觉在灼烧
The next second, it's entombed in ice.
下一秒 就如同躺在冰窖里
Every pain sensor in your body is firing at the same time
你身体中的每一个痛点都同时达到最大负载
until agony isn't even a word or a concept-
直到痛苦不再是一个词 或者一个概念
it's your only reality. You hallucinate.
而变成你的全部现实 你会产生幻觉
You dream of death.
你会梦到死亡
And then the race begins.
而这时真正的比赛才刚刚开始
Can your body claw its way back in time
你的身体能经受住这次的打击吗?
before the hostile organisms and parasites
能赶在那些致命的致病菌与寄生虫
claim you permanently?
永远胜利之前重新启动吗?
Win, you live. Lose, you die.
赢了 你还能活 输了 你必死无疑
Now what are we doing here, Wilson?
现在 我们到底在干什么呢 Wilson?
Kidney number one looks good.
这边的肾看起来没问题
Which means we'll probably take the biopsy from two.
看来我们可能得在另一边取活检样本了
Hey, you're doing great.
嘿 你表现好极了
Brave as always.
一直都很勇敢哟
Pretty cool, eh?
好玩吧?
You want to try?
想不想自己试试?
What's wrong? My chest hurts.
- 怎么了? - 我胸口疼
It's definitely not her kidneys. It's okay.
- 绝对不是肾脏的问题 - 没事的
Promise this'll taste just as good coming up as it did going down.
保证喝下去吐出来味道一样好哟
If things go wrong, I just want you to know-
如果有什么不测 我只想让你知道...
If you're gonna say that you've always been secretly gay for me,
如果你想说你一直对我有不纯洁的想法
everyone always just kind of assumed it.
告诉你说大家其实一直都是这么想的
I just want you to know...
我只想让你知道...
That I appreciate the risk you're taking...
对于你冒这么大的风险 我很感激...
Pumping a human being full of lethal chemicals in your living room.
在你家客厅里给别人身体内 输入致命的化学物质什么的
If I die, it probably won't go over well with your probation officer.
如果我死了 保释官那边你可不好交待
That's not gonna be an issue.
不会有问题的
I'm glad at least one of us is confident.
真高兴至少我们之中还有一个自信的
Not me.
才不是我呢
I've already identified a couple of spots to dump your body
我早已经检视好几个抛尸地点了
if this goes south.
如果你挂了的话咱也有个准备
I've always enjoyed Trinity Park.
我一直觉得三一公园挺不错的
It does have a nice access to the lake.
是离湖挺近的哈
Muscle spasms already?
已经开始肌肉痉挛了?
No. It's nothing really.
没 啥事也没有
Good news.
好消息
Takes most people two bags to get to that stage.
一般人要两袋药下去才能到这个阶段呢
You're way ahead of schedule.
您的时间表真是大大提前了
You'll think it's stupid. That hasn't stopped you before.
- 你会觉得我在说蠢话 - 没人拦着你
I just always thought,
可我老是想着
when I got old or sick,
当我老了 病了
I'd have a wife or kids to look after me.
会有妻子儿女来照顾我
And in this scenario, are your loving wife and kids
在那个情景下 你充满爱意的老婆孩子
holding the life support cord,
是在一手按着维生设备的开关
or are they thumbing through your will?
一手扒拉你的遗嘱么?
I'm in it, right?
这情景里总有我的吧?
You have everything you need right here.
你要的所有一切都在你眼前了
We both do.
准确地说是我们俩要的所有一切
Painkiller. Industrial strength.
止痛药 工业级效果
Level: Awesome.
剂量 超赞
We're on vacation.
这才算度假
That is nice.
这还真不错
Her kidneys are fine.
她的肾脏没问题
I don't think we're looking at side effects from the Lex-2.
我觉得不是Lex 2的副作用
She's prone to respiratory infection.
她的呼吸系统易受感染
- Pneumonia? - No persistent cough, chills, or excess sweating.
- 肺炎? - 无持续咳嗽 发冷或大量出汗
What about a pulmonary embolism? Fits coughing up blood, but a clot?
- 肺部栓塞呢? - 符合咳血 但是血栓又是怎么回事呢?
From what? Bruising from when she fell off the carousel.
- 哪里来的? - 从旋转木马上跌下来造成的挫伤
Contusion damages a deep vein, causes a clot.
碰撞造成深层静脉损伤 形成血栓
A piece breaks off, travels to her lungs.
有一小块掉下来 跑进了她的肺里
We need to get her on heparin now.
得马上给她上肝素
Another embolism could cause a heart attack or a stroke.
再一次的栓塞可能造成她心脏病发或痉挛
What's wrong? Is it Emily?
怎么了? 是Emily吗?
Sort of.
算是吧
You can't do this.
你不能这样做
I'm taking her to Mercy.
我要把她送到梅西医院去
Everything you people have done has just made her worse.
你们所有的治疗都让她的病情更加恶化了
You don't have the right. We have joint custody.
- 你没这个权力 - 我们对她有共同监护权
Where was my right when you were treating our daughter like a lab rat?
当你把她当小白鼠一样摆布的时候 我的权力又在哪里呢!
should ????
我如果不那样她会死的!
Stop it.
别吵了
Your daughter deserves better than this.
你们女儿不应该被这样对待
It's okay, sweetie.
没事的 宝贝儿
Mommy and I are just gonna talk.
妈妈和我只是在好好说话
Okay? You want to get some candy?
- 好吗? - 想吃糖吗?
We believe Emily has a clot in her lungs.
我们觉得Emily的肺里有个血栓
If you leave now, she could die before her new doctors are even up to speed.
如果你现在带她走 在她的新医生接手之前 她就会有生命危险
From her A-T? From the fall off the carousel.
- 因为A-T综合征? - 因为从木马上摔下来
Now can we just stop blaming each other and do the right thing here?
我们能不能别再互相指责 好好考虑女儿的事情?
You're really gonna equate the two?
这两件事能比吗?
No, you were giving her two minutes of fun.
你不过让她高兴了两分钟而已
I was trying to save her life.
而我是在救她的命!
What's her best friend's name?
她最好的朋友叫什么名字?
What's the name of her favorite teacher?
她最喜欢的老师叫什么名字?
Why does she hate that stuffed animal you gave her?
为什么她讨厌你给她那个玩具?
She's been having nightmares about penguins all month.
她整整一个月都在做关于企鹅的噩梦
What's her blood type?
她什么血型?
Rh factor? Her serum immunoglobulin levels?
Rh因子指数呢? 血清免疫球蛋白指数如何?
I don't care. Those are letters and numbers.
我才不关心呢 这只是无意义的字母和数字罢了
- That's not her. - What about the variant in her e14 ATM intergenic promoter region?
- 这不是她 - 还有她的e14ATM突变基因在间基因位的指数呢?
Because that's what's killing your daughter.
因为这就是正在杀死她的病症
Unless I can find a way to reactivate it.
除非我找出重新激活它的办法
Just make her better.
快让她好起来吧
You don't look too good, mister.
你看起来可不好呀 先生
How did you get in here? The door.
- 你怎么进来的? - 从门里进来的
Are you, like, sick or something?
你是不是病了啊?
Where's House?
House在哪儿?
Where are your parents?
你父母呢?
Oh, I know you. You live in the building, right?
我认得你 你住在这栋楼里的是吧?
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
You don't remember?
你不记得了吗?
House.
House
You promised me I'd go home again, Dr. Wilson.
你保证过我一定能回家的 Wilson
You said it wasn't my fault.
你说不是我的错
It wasn't, John.
真的不是你的错啊 John
If I didn't do nothing wrong, why did I die?
那如果我没有错 我怎么死了呢?
I don't know.
我不知道
Look...
我...
I shouldn't have done this.
我不该这样的
Am I dead?
我死了吗?
Not yet.
还没呢
It just feels that way. Are you okay?
只是感觉有点像死了而已 你还好吧?
I mean, apart from the pain, vomiting, diarrhea, and cramps?
我是说除了剧痛 呕吐 腹泻以及抽筋之外?
I worked six months in a research lab after med school.
医学院毕业之后 我在一家研究实验室工作了六个月
You get so focused.
人的精神就能那么集中
Once I didn't eat for two days.
有一回 我两天都没吃饭
It's easy to forget what actually matters.
有时候挺容易人就忘掉真正有意义的事情了
I didn't.
我没忘
Yeah, it sucks I got her the wrong doll, but...
是啊 我给她买的玩具不对 不过...
Good news.
好消息
Emily's lungs are clear.
Emily的肺没事
No clot. And bad news. We still don't know what's happening to her.
- 没有血栓 - 坏消息是 我们还是不知道她怎么了
Whatever it is, there's liver involvement.
不管是什么 已经发展到肝脏了
Her eyes are jaundiced.
她起了黄疸
Her liver's failing.
她的肝脏不行了
We found a blockage in her hepatic vein,
我们在肝静脉中发现了阻塞
which is restricting blood flow to her liver. Polycythemia vera?
- 限制了肝脏的血液循环 - 真性红细胞增多症
Red blood counts are normal.
红细胞数正常
Could be some sort of connective tissue disorder.
可能是连接组织出了问题
What if-
如果...
what if we're just seeing the end result
我们只不过是看到了
of her condition?
她这种病的最后结果呢?
She's unique.
她太特殊了
One screwed-up gene from each of us.
从我们俩每人身上遗传了一个不好的基因
Let's stick with our process.
我们还是着眼于她现在的状况吧
I shouldn't be here.
我不该在这儿的
What are we missing? Advanced Lyme disease.
- 我们到底漏掉什么了? - 进阶莱姆症
Would have seen it in the blood. He said advanced.
- 血检应该看出来的 - 他说的是进阶
We wouldn't pick it up in her blood if it's in her organs and nervous system now.
如果已经进展到她的器官和神经系统中了 血液里就看不出来了
It fits everything but the nosebleed.
一切都符合 除了流鼻血
But why is it attacking now, all at once?
但为什么它现在才开始火力全开呢?
What's changed?
到底什么变了?
Elizabeth has.
Elizabeth变了
She stopped giving Emily the Lex-2.
她不再给Emily用Lex 2了
It's an aminoglycoside antibiotic.
那是一种氨基糖苷类的抗生素
It's what was keeping the Lyme in check.
能够抑制她的莱姆症
We need to start her on amoxicillin.
我们得赶紧给她上阿莫西林
You lied. Doesn't taste better coming back up.
你这个骗子 吐出来一点也没有喝下去的味道好
Here's another one. You look good.
再骗你一次 你气色好极了
What's the white blood cell count?
白细胞数怎么样?
It's down to 1,000, still dropping.
已经降到了1000 而且还在降
I need more morphine.
我需要更多吗啡
We're out.
吗啡已经用完了
You've been using my personal supply of painkillers for the last eight hours.
之前的八个小时你用的都是我私藏的止痛药
You have- you have enough for both of us?
你私藏的...够我们俩人用吗?
I've got enough stashed around here for a minyan.
我囤的货足够给你这个兔崽子用的
Just remember they're a gift.
给我记住了 这是送你的礼物
So it's rude to keep throwing them up.
老是吐出来是大不敬
Found that out with those candlesticks you got me.
我是从你送我那些个蜡烛上悟到的
We think it's Lyme.
我们觉得是莱姆症
I would have seen signs of that. Not if the Lex-2 was keeping it in check.
- 我应该早会看到症状的啊 - 如果Lex 2一直抑制着就不会
We live in the city. We don't have pets.
我们住在城市里 也没有养宠物
She's never even been in the woods.
她也从来没有往树林里去过
Yes, I have. With daddy.
我去过的 和爸爸一起
I should have told you, but I know how you feel about it.
我知道我该跟你说的 但我清楚你会怎么反应
I grew up hunting with my dad.
我是和我爸一起打猎长大的
I wanted to share it with my daughter at least once.
我也想和我自己的女儿至少分享一次这种经历
We only took pictures. You don't need to be mad.
我们只是照了几张照片 妈妈别生气
Maybe we should step outside. No.
- 我们还是出去吧 - 不用
We can't protect her from everything.
我们不可能时时刻刻保护她
I assume you'll need a lumbar puncture to confirm.
我估计这得要脊椎穿刺才能确诊吧
You lost a contact?
隐形眼镜丢了一只啊?
Going to the little boy's room.
我想去厕所
They're called adult diapers for a reason.
成人尿布这个命名是有理由的
Use it.
有就用啊
I did, and if you think I'm gonna let you change me-
我是用了 但如果你觉得我会让你给我换尿布...
It's okay. I'm a doctor. Just leave me alone.
- 没关系的 我是医生啊 - 别管我
It's pathetic.
真可悲
I'm pathetic.
我真可悲啊
An oncologist with cancer. Of all the things that could be killing me...
得了癌症的肿瘤学家 这世界上所有能杀死我的东西...
It's like the universe is giving me the big middle finger.
这简直就是世界在向我竖中指!
The universe doesn't care-
这世界一点都不关心
Why me?
为什么是我呢?
I'm always telling my patients
我总是告诉病人
not to torture themselves, because there's no answer.
别折磨自己想这想那 因为跟本就没有答案
Sound advice. It's cruel advice.
- 这个建议很正确啊 - 是很残忍!
They were just trying to make sense of what was happening to them,
他们只是想弄清楚自己到底为什么会得病
and I'm there telling them not to bother?
而我却告诉他们别白费力气了吗?
I should have spent my life being more like you.
我应该像你一样生活
Should have been a manipulative, self-centered,
我应该做一个诡计多端 自我中心
narcissistic ass who brought misery to everything and everyone
顾影自怜的混蛋 把不幸传播给他身边的
in his life.
每一个人和每一件事
You'd still have cancer. Yeah!
- 可你还依然会得癌症啊 - 是啊!
But at least I'd feel like I deserved it.
但我至少会觉得我罪有应得!
Do you think my parents will get back together?
你觉得我爸妈会和好吗?
I don't know.
我不知道
I'm sure they love each other, but- They only fight about me.
他们彼此很相爱 但老为我的事情吵架
That's because they care so much.
那是因为他们特别特别关心你啊
So maybe when I die,
那么如果我死了
they'll get back together.
他们就会和好了
Emily, what's wrong? I can't move my arm.
- Emily 怎么了? - 我的手动不了了
Just keep your arms up for me.
把手抬起来好吗?
What's happening to her? She's having a stroke.
- 她怎么了? - 她中风了
Okay, your heart rate's up, BP's tanking.
你的心跳过快 血压过低
White blood count's at 500. We have to go to the hospital now.
白血球数只剩下500了 我们得赶紧去医院了
No. I don't have the equipment or the meds to handle this.
- 不要 - 我没有急救的药物和设备啊
No. Win or lose.
不 要么赢 要么输
Win or lose. That was the deal.
要么赢 要么输 我们说好的
That was the deal when there was an "or".
我们说好的是有得选的时候
You can't win this.
你现在已经赢不了了啊
No.
不
No. I'd rather die here.
不要 我宁愿死在这儿
Not in an ambulance.
我不要死在救护车里
Not in a hospital.
我不要死在医院里
Please, you can't do that to me.
求求你 别那么对我
I can't-
我不要...
House...
House...
Please.
求求你
Promise me that you won't do that to me.
答应我你不会那样对我
Promise me.
答应我啊!
Okay, I promise.
好 我答应你
Stroke.
中风
Blockage in her hepatic vein, coughing blood,
肝静脉阻塞 咯血
trouble breathing, and Raynaud's.
呼吸困难 以及雷诺病
If we hadn't already ruled it out, it sounds like textbook pulmonary embolism.
如果不是已经排除了 这听起来简直是教科书式的肺部栓塞
What mimics a clot but isn't a clot?
什么像肿瘤但又不是肿瘤呢?
Fungal infection. Her CSF was clean.
- 真菌感染? - CSF无显示
No bacterial or fungal markers. Anyone tried calling House?
- 无细菌或真菌感染的迹象 - 有人试过给House打电话吗?
Not picking up. Or returning messages or texts.
- 他根本不接电话 - 留言和短信也不回
We're on our own here, so just give me some theories we can use.
我们得靠自己了 快说几个能用的理论吧
Hematologic malignancies.
恶性血液病
A- T patients are more prone to that form of cancer.
A- T症患者极易患这种癌症
You think cancer would present and kill her in three days?
你觉得癌症会在三天之内杀死她吗?
Not cancer.
不是癌症
But a tumor could act like a clot.
但肿瘤却有可能显示出血栓的症状
An atrial myxoma.
心房粘液瘤
A primary heart tumor.
长在心脏上的肿瘤
The swinging motion of the myxoma intermittently blocked the flow of blood through the right atrium.
心房的间歇性收缩阻塞了右边动脉的血流
Inflow blockage stagnated the hepatic vein, which clotted and caused liver failure.
流入内循环的阻塞物堵住了肝静脉 然后形成血栓 造成肝衰竭
Outflow blockage caused the Raynaud's phenomenon and stroke.
而外循环中的阻塞物则造成了 雷诺病以及中风
Pieces of the tumor broke off and lodged in the lungs,
肿瘤的残片脱落 聚集在了肺部
causing Emily's breathing problems and the coughing blood.
造成Emily呼吸困难以及咳血
We'll remove the tumor surgically, and hopefully the biopsy reveals it's benign.
我们会手术切除肿瘤 然后希望活检结果是良性
Wow. You- you really look like crap.
哇哦 你...你看起来真的糟透了
Been fighting a cold lately.
近来在和感冒勇敢战斗呢
Seven to ten days for the swelling to go down.
七到十天能消肿
Then we rescan and schedule the surgery.
然后再重新扫描并安排手术
I seem to recall
我隐约记得
I said some things to you- You talked a lot.
- 我跟你说了一些话... - 你嘴就没停
I stopped listening
你说到你害怕海豚之后
after you confessed your fear of dolphins.
我就再没听了
Can we just tone down the bromance a few notches? My leg is killing me.
咱把这浓郁的狗男男气氛先降温一下行不? 我腿疼死了
One last favor.
最后帮我个忙
I'd like to actually make it to the bathroom this time.
我想还是去厕所了断吧
I thought you said you had plenty of Vicodin.
我以为你说过你的维柯丁足够多呢
Everybody lies.
每个人都说谎
So the way I felt, you feel that, what,
那就是说我那时的感觉 对你来说
most of the time?
大部分时候都是那样的?
It really does suck being you, doesn't it? At least I don't have cancer.
- 当你真是糟透了 是吧? - 至少老子还没癌症呢
The tumor was benign.
肿瘤是良性的
And we were able to remove all of it.
而我们已经把它全部切除了
Does this mean I'm not sick anymore?
这是说我已经没病了吗?
No, honey.
不 宝贝儿
The tumor didn't cause
肿瘤不是
your genetic condition.
你基因缺损的原因
You're still sick.
你依然有病
But we never let that stop us before, right?
不过我们一直也都能处理得了 是吧?
So what do you want to do when we get out of here?
出院以后想去哪里玩?
Have you been to the aquarium?
去过水族馆了吗?
It's pretty cool.
可好玩啦
Can we go, daddy? You bet.
- 爸爸 我们能去吗? - 还用说嘛
Me too?
我也能去吗?
Can she come with us?
妈妈能一起去吗?
You know mommy never has to ask.
你知道妈妈从来都是不用问就能加入的哟
I'll see you at lunch.
午饭见
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入